A Guide to the Records of George Bernard Lorraine, ca. 1925-1976
Library of Virginia
- Oversize
  - Virginia real estate maps and plats
    - Gloucester County
      - Thrift Farm: Eddie C. Frazier, n.d. (folder 18)
      - Ware Hall: Thomas R. Benson, 1959 (folder 19)
      - Warner Hall: J.S. Crockett, 1942-1948 (folder 20)
      - West End: Oliver B. Whiting, 1951 (folder 21)
      - White Hall: John Hayes, 1946-1957 (folder 22)
      - Wilson Creek Farm: Pat Carter, 1967 (folder 23)
      - Dutton, Frank Bland: 1947-1950 (folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 26)
    - Goochland County
      - Bolling Island Farm: Joe Crenshaw, 1942-1962 (folders 27 and 28)
      - Elk Hill: Buford Scott, 1937-1960 (folder 29)
      - Elk Hill: Mrs. Pitts, 1947-1949 (folder 30)
      - Fairfield: James H. McDonough, 1942-1959 (folder 31)
      - Old Elk Hill: Paul H. Dupertuis, 1957-1965 (folder 32)
      - Orapax Farm: G.S. Evans, 1952-1955 (folder 33)
      - Sabot Hill Farm: Bank of Giles County, 1935-1936 (folder 34)
      - Senito Farm: Maynor Baltimore, 1937-1941 (folder 35)
      - Bryan, J. St. George: 1937 (folder 1)
      - Waldrop, Byron R.: 217 acres, 1935 (folder 2)
      - Wilson, Charles B.: farm, 1941-1955 (folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 5)
    - Halifax County
      - Bellevue: H.G. Edmunds, 1948-1949 (folder 6)
      - Tarover: W.B. Caldwell, 1967 (folder 7)
    - Hanover County
      - Bullfield: Taze Saunders, 1928-1936 (folder 8)
      - Courtland Farm: G.R. Hudgins, 1936 (folder 9)
      - Edgewood: William C. Noland, 1938 (folder 10)
      - Graymont: Mr. Gray, n.d. (folder 11)
      - Lewis Level: Jourdan Woolfolk, 1941 (folder 12)
      - Maplewood Farm: W.B. Abrams, 1953-1955 (folder 13)
      - Oak Grove: George R. Horne, 1937-1940 (folder 14)
      - Pleasant Level: W.G. Powers, 1940 (folder 15)
      - Retreat: E.J. Rosenburg, 1944 (folder 16)
      - Rocketts: C. Lukaszkiewicz, 1935-1942 (folder 17)
      - Rose Hill: William E. Langford, 1938-1952 (folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 19)
    - Henrico County
      - Runymeade Farm: Edward S. Schmidt, 1938 (folder 20)
      - Walnut Hill Farm: Stephen and Frank D. Beveridge, 1940 (folder 21)
      - Richeson, Frank S.: 26 acres, 1940-1942 (folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous service stations: 1953 (folder 23)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 25)
    - Highland County
      - Lazy K. Ranch: R.C. Kendrick, 1950-1955 (folder 26)
    - Isle of Wight County
      - Rocks on James: Dale E. Snyder, 1936-1944 (folder 27)
      - Southport: Hampton Roads Waterfront Corporation, 1929 (folder 28)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 29)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 30)
    - James City County
      - Riverview: H.L. Bloomberg, 1942 (folder 1)
      - McCartney, H.G.: 78 acres, 1949 (folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 4)
    - King and Queen County
      - Erin: M.M. Sutherland, 1965 (folder 4)
      - Hockley: Mr. Elliott, 1944 (folder 5)
    - King George County
      - Bundick, Clarkson U.: 72 acres, n.d. (folder 6)
      - Woodstock: Robert Sharp, 1952 (folder 7)
      - Boothe, W.R.: 1960 (folder 8)
    - King William County
      - Brick House Landing Farm: Walter E. Ruprecht, 1943-1953 (folder 9)
      - Ferry Farm: Adolph Prochazka, 1965 (folder 10)
      - North Point: John C. Moore, 1961-1963 (folder 11)
      - Windsor Shade: Francis W. Welch, 1932-1936 (folder 12)
      - Gwathney, Mary Burnley: 1958-1959 (folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 14)
    - Lancaster County
      - Apple Grove Farm: Hulbert E. Flowers, 1961 (folder 15)
      - Belmont: R.O. Norris, 1937-1942 (folder 16)
      - Enon Hall: Mr. McKesson, 1964 (folder 17)
      - Epping Forest: James D. Jessie, 1958-1960 (folder 18)
      - Laurel Point: n.d. (folder 5)
      - Level Fields: W.R. Smith, 1946-1959 (folder 19)
      - Midway: Charles G. Snead, 1935-1958 (folders 20 and 21)
      - Monaskon: James A. Tarhutton, 1954-1960 (folder 22)
      - Old Crawford: William M. Crawford, 1937-1956 (folder 23)
      - Old House Point: Mary Nash Goodwin, 1948 (folder 24)
      - Riverview Farm: W. Lucius Sanders, 1956 (folder 25)
      - Towles Point: W.C. Towles, 1958-1962 (folder 26)
      - Verville: Walter Oliver, 1965 (folder 27)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 28)
    - Louisa County
      - Belmont: Sidney E. Sharwood, 1941-1944 (folder 29)
      - Dixie Knoll: F.J. Dickinson, 1956 (folder 30)
      - Hawkwood: Richard S. Reynolds, 1946-1951 (folder 31)
      - Healing Springs: H.H. Greve, 1937-1941 (folder 32)
      - Mansfield: Bruce V. Boxley, 1952 (folder 33)
      - Clark, Mr.: 175 acres, 1959 (folder 34)
    - Madison County
      - Rock Hill: E.J. Nottingham, 1934-1938 (folder 35)
    - Mathews County
      - Fair Harbor: Willard F. Day, 1959 (folder 36)
      - Hopemont: E. Hope Norton, 1962-1963 (folder 6)
      - Rayemdor: Raymond R. Richardson, 1935-1952 (folder 37)
      - Walnut Point: A. William Smith, 1955-1962 (folder 1)
      - Foster, E.A.: n.d. (folder 2)
      - Mead, Harry Judson: 30 acres, n.d. (folder 3)
      - Rilee, R.M.: 143 acres, 1944-1950 (folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 6)
    - Mecklenburg County
      - Merry Mount: H.O. Swink, 1942 (folder 7)
    - Middlesex County
      - Berryville Farm: F.W. Scott, 1947 (folder 8)
      - Deer Chase: M.A. Pratt, 1937 (folder 9)
      - Fairfield Farm: S.L. Sinnott, 1938-1940 (folder 10)
      - Fairfield Farm: Eastman O'Riordan, n.d. (folder 11)
      - Gray Point: J.I. Adams, 1944-1945 (folder 12)
      - Kilmer Point: Harold Barnes, 1962 (folder 13)
      - Laurel Bank: A.J. Chewning, 1958 (folder 14)
      - Locust Grove: James Keith, 1932-1943 (folder 15)
      - Martieu: H. Laurie Smith, 1947-1952 (folder 16)
      - North End Plantation: John G. McGurk, 1966 (folder 17)
      - Remlick Hall: Alexander M. Robb, 1940-1943 (folder 18)
      - Stove Neck Point: 1933 (folder 19)
      - Daniel, S.W.: 112 acres, 1936 (folder 20)
      - Hunter, E.M.: 1948 (folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 23)
    - Nansemond County
      - Cedar Crest Hall: James E. Culbreth, 1969 (folder 24)
    - Nelson County
      - Forest Edge: Mr. Burruss, 1964 (folder 25)
      - Inglewood: R.T. Carleton, 1958 (folder 26)
      - Nelmont: Phillip T. Harris, 1949 (folder 27)
      - Oakland Farm: Frances L. Towers, 1955 (folder 28)
      - Red Apple Orchard: George B. Clifford & Company, 1946 (folder 29)
    - New Kent County
      - Mountcastle: Carroll D. Hagan, 1934-1939 (folder 30)
      - Rose Cottage: L.T. Southall, 1954 (folder 31)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 32)
    - Northampton County
      - Vaucluse: Roy Wheeler (realtor), n.d. (folder 33)
    - Northumberland County
      - Fauntleroy: Housing Investments Corporation, 1933-1944 (folder 34)
      - Goodman property: 1957 (folder 35)
      - Locksley Hall: Locksley Hall Corporation, 1957 (folders 7 and 8)
      - Red Gate: Joseph LeGrand, 1960 (folder 1)
      - Salt Pond: W.A. Whitaker, 1936-1950 (folder 2)
      - Texas Farm: Edward L. Traylor, 1957 (folder 3)
      - Tranquilitiy: John C. Little, 1961 (folder 9)
      - Walnut Point: James Lewis, 1961 (folder 4)
      - West End: Henry G. Thorndike, 1951-1964 (folder 5)
      - Fisher, Mr.: 8 acres, 1965 (folder 6)
      - Gold, Douglas: 74 acres, 1965-1972 (folder 7)
      - Peverly, S.D.: 471 acres, 1957 (folder 8)
      - Spaven, George N.: 1961 (folder 9)
      - Thomas, William G.: deed, 1958-1963 (folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 11)
    - Nottoway County
      - Blackstone Military Academy: J.H. Clay, 1948 (folder 12)
      - Fair Oaks Farm: Jerry C. Stroup, 1967 (folder 13)
    - Orange County
      - Barboursville: John B. Gordon, 1958 (folder 14)
      - Greenwood: K.S. Edwards, 1959 (folder 15)
      - Hawfield: John S. Rixey, 1936, 1947-1952 (folder 16)
      - Mount Sharon: R.C. Slaughter, 1935 (folder 17)
      - Niehl, Harriet W.: 6 acres, 1948 (folder 18)
    - Powhatan County
      - Fighting Creek: 1968 (folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 10)
    - Prince Edward County
      - Rotherwood: F.W. Shanaberger, 1951-1954 (folder 21)
    - Prince George County
      - Willow Hill: John H. Trant, 1950-1952 (folder 22)
      - Cutchin, Mr.: 253 acres, 1951 (folder 23)
      - Dougherty, C.H.: 15 acres, 1971 (folder 24)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 25)
    - Prince William County
      - Herring, G.W.: 640 acres, 1945 (folder 11)
    - Princess Anne County
      - Bird Neck Point: Bird Neck Realty Company, n.d. (folder 26)
      - Croatan Club: 1933-1939 (folder 12)
      - Beavis, James O.: 345 1/4 acres (folder 27)
      - Parker, Mr.: 1 acre, 1960 (folder 28)
    - Rappahannock County
      - Mount Ida: S.E. Hening, 1952 (folder 29)
    - Richmond County
      - Shandy Hall: Fred Durham, 1938-1961 (folder 13)
      - Woodberry: D.E. Foster, 1965 (folder 30)
    - Roanoke County
      - Bottom Creek tract: 900 acres, n.d. (folder 31)
    - Rockbridge County
      - Winfree, P.B.: 801 acres, 1964 (folder 32)
    - Rockingham County
      - Court Manor: Canning Land Company, 1960 (folder 33)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 34)
    - Spotsylvania County
      - Pine Forest: H.E. DeJarnette, 1949-1962 (folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 2)
    - Surry County
      - Claremont Manor: Millicent A. Rogers, 1948-1950 (folder 3)
      - Flying Point Farm: 275 acres, 1951 (folder 4)
      - Pleasant Point: Willis Morrison, 1935-1949 (folder 5)
      - Quicohanna: Ashley P. Cutchin, 1968 (folder 6)
      - Guza, S.H.: 1099 acres, 1952 (folder 7)
      - Hopper, J. Lewis: 30-35 acres, n.d. (folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 9)
    - Sussex County
      - Montrose: Robert H. Stephenson, 1964 (folder 10)
      - Oakland: Lucy M. Raines, 1961 (folder 11)
    - Westmoreland County
      - Arlington Farm: John P. Cooke, 1959 (folder 12)
      - Bleak Hall: William C. Nalle, 1937-1940 (folder 13)
      - Bushfield: Mark S. Willing, 1940-1944 (folder 14)
      - Church Point: 175 acres, n.d. (folder 15)
      - Claymount: Gillette Conner, 1962 (folder 16)
      - The Glebe: Irwin H. Linton, 1963 (folder 17)
      - Wilton: Arthur W. Roberts, 1954-1962 (folder 18)
      - Wirtland: Burton H. Slocum, 1957 (folder 19)
      - Bronson, Howard C.: 10 acres, 1950-1951 (folder 20)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 21)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 22)
    - York County
      - Famsed Point: Florence A. Monfalcone, 1967 (folder 23)
      - Waterview: Fred Hodges, 1944-1949 (folder 24)
      - Jones, Ben: 37 acres, 1956 (folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 26)
  - Out-of-state real estate maps and plats
    - Alabama
      - Vredenburgh Saw Mill Company (Vredenburgh): 1946-1949 (folder 15)
    - Florida
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 27)
    - Maryland
      - Brinkley Farm: Joseph B. Brinkley, 1943 (folder 28)
      - Mount Republican: 400 acres, 1936-1959 (folder 29)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 30)
    - New York
      - Driftwoods: Countess Alexandre de Leslie, n.d. (folder 31)
    - North Carolina
      - Mayview Manor (Blowing Rock): n.d. (folder 32)
      - Fort Caswell Harbor (Southport): 1933 (folder 33)
      - Martin, George N. (Tyrrell County): 5416 acres, 1956 (folder 34)
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 35)
      - Miscellaneous real estate listings (folder 36)
    - Tennessee
      - Miscellaneous letter file (folder 37)
    - United States Virgin Islands
      - St. Croix subdivision: 1973 (folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous maps and plats and other miscellaneous
    - Virginia County Primary and Secondary Highway Systems maps (folder 1)
    - Virginia Official Highway map (folder 2)
    - United States Army Corps of Engineers Geological Survey Maps for Virginia (folder 3)
    - United States Army Corps of Engineers Geological Survey Maps for Virginia (folder 4)
    - United States Army Corps of Engineers Geological Survey Maps for Virginia (folder 5)
    - Virginia Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries: United States Army Corps of Engineers map of Accomack County (folder 6)
    - Phelps, Ben: plat of land in Clarke County area, 1961 (folder 7)
    - R.T. Marsh home tract: Lilian Lumber Company, n.d. (folder 8)
    - Louisa County soil survey (folder 16)
    - Unidentified property aerial photograph (folder 9)
    - Unidentified property cul-de-sac map (folder 10)
    - Map of Virginia showing the geography and physical features of the state (folder 17)
    - Gazette-Journal (newspaper), Garden Week supplement, 28 April 1955 (folder 11)
    - Virginia Gazette (newspaper), Publick Observer supplement, April 1975 (folder 12)
    - Fitzhugh-Grymes family genealogical chart (folder 13)
    - Richmond Times-Dispatch, Historic Garden Week supplement, 16 April 1972 (folder 14)
    - Harper's Weekly reissues, 11 and 18 April 1863 (folder 15)
    - Norfolk area tourist map (folder 16)
    - Unidentified property photograph (folder 17)
    - Unidentified property map (folder 18)
    - Stan Fenelle drawing of Secretariat (folder 19)
    - Rosendale Natural Cement advertisement, 1954 (folder 20)
    - Northumberland Echo (newspaper), 26 Oct. 1967 (folder 21)
    - Richmond Times-Dispatch, Jamestown Festival supplement, 31 March 1957 (folder 22)
    - Richmond Times-Dispatch, Historic Garden Week supplement, 15 April 1962 (folder 23)
    - A.A.A. Historical map of Virginia, n.d. (folder 24)
    - East Coast road maps (folder 25)
- Miscellaneous business correspondence and records (Box 150-157)
  This series contains correspondence exchanged between Lorraine Real Estate and other brokers and realtors, property owners and buyers, advertisers, attorneys, businesses, organizations, and national, state and city government officials concerning unidentified properties and non-real estate related matters. There are also employee and fiscal records, specifically advertising correspondence and receipts, bank checks, deposits, and statements, 1962-1963, employee sales and commission records, 1963, employee tax records, 1962-1964, interoffice correspondence, 1957, 1974, and correspondence, 1942-1950, with F. Virginius Watkins, Lorraine's real estate attorney. Also contains promotional correspondence and pamphlets, receipts, house keys, a scrapbook of unidentified property photographs arranged by property value, and a list of millionaires in selected states compiled by R. L. Polks and Company in 1940.
  - Buyer correspondence (Box 150)
    - Arnest, Harry Lee: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Bodeep, Joseph: 1963 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Carter, M.H.: 1959 (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Davis, G.L.: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Hilleary, Scott T.: 1972 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Hyle, David P.: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Irmish, George W.: 1969-1975 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Kirby, James L.: 1956-1966, 1975 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Long, A.C.: 1957-1963 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Lore, G.I.: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - McCready, Donald: 1967 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Maldini, Rose: 1974 (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Mead, M.F.E.: 1958 (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Nelson, Craig: 1951-1961 (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - Period Houses: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - Pratt, Richard R.: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Rodriguez, J.: 1965 (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Ruegg, Albert A.: 1972 (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - Sargent, Leonard: 1960 (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - Searfoss, Mark: 1975 (Box 150, Folder 20)
    - Simmons, F.M.: 1939 (Box 150, Folder 21)
    - Thomas, John Tyler: 1963 (Box 150, Folder 22)
    - Tidewater Veneer Company: 1955-1957 (Box 150, Folder 23)
    - Toh, Virginia: 1960 (Box 150, Folder 24)
    - Virginia Commission of Game and Inland Fisheries: 1956-1959 (Box 150, Folder 25)
    - Wilkins, John: 1957 (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous: 1957 (Box 150, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous: 1973 (Box 150, Folder 28)
  - Broker and owner correspondence (Box 151)
    - Barkley, George H.: 1974 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Canning Land Company: 1953, 1957-1966 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Clark, W.B.: 1966-1967 (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - Cooke, Katherine G.: 1963 (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - Copland, A.G.: 1951 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Dortch, William B.: 1960-1962 (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Ferry, George B.: 1942-1951 (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - Howe, Lillian: 1952 (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - Montgomery, Ian S.: 1965-1973 (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - Norris, Robert M.: 1962-1964 (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Pates-Massey: 1958 (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - Period Houses: 1971-1975 (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - Walker, Alex W.: 1957 (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - Webb and Knapp, Inc.: 1954-1956 (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - Wheeler, Roy: 1967, 1975 (Box 151, Folder 15)
    - Wheeler, Roy: miscellaneous listings, n.d. (Box 151, Folder 16)
    - Zerkel, L. Ferdinand: 1943, 1951, 1954 (Box 151, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous: 1934, 1955, 1957-1976 (Box 151, Folder 18)
  - Fiscal and employee records (Box 153-157)
    - Bank checks and statements: December 1962 - December 1963 (Box 152)
    - Bank deposits and income reports: 1963, 1966 (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of exemption of personal motor vehicle from gasoline purchase limitations: 1974 (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - Chinnis, Betsy W. (employee): 1973 (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Employee sales and commission records: 1963 (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - Employee tax records: 1962-1964 (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Hendricks, William C. (employee): 1962 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous advertising correspondence and receipts, 1942-1947, 1957-1962, 1970-1975 (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous interoffice correspondence: 1957, 1974 (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Moffatt, Jessie M. (employee): n.d. (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Parker, P. Walter (employee): 1963 (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - Watkins, F. Virginius (attorney): 1942-1950 (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 154)
    - House keys (Box 155-156)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified property photograph scrapbook (Box 157)
- Publications (Box 158-162)
  Consists of government and organizational publications, periodicals, tourist pamphlets and guidebooks, Mary Wingfield Scott's Richmond Times-Dispatch articles, 1940-1942, on historic buildings, clippings of "Old Dominion Oddities by Allen" published in the Richmond Times-Dispatch, and a speech, 6 June 1931, by Claude G. Bowers at the unveiling of the bust of John Tyler in the State Capital in Richmond. Some of the periodicals contain advertisements for George Lorraine's brokerage.
- File cards (Box 163-173)
  This part of the collection holds file cards pertaining to certain real estate properties. Arranged alphabetically by property name, or in some cases location or owner's surname, these cards include information concerning the Historical Virginia Building Survey, estates owned by New Yorkers in the United States South, Virginia churches, and reference sources for individual properties. This series also includes some postcards of Virginia properties.